This is a work of fiction. Names, characters,
places and incidents either are products of the
author’s imagination or are used fictitiously. Any
resemblance to actual events or locales or
persons, living or dead, is entirely coincidental.
Incoming mail
Sister Centipede
Re:Re: Where are you?
Aki
Where are you?
Iru-O support notification
Iru-O Support
Mom
Iru-O support notification
Sister Centipede
Re:Re: Where are you?
Aki
Where are you?
Iru-O Support
Mom
Incoming mail
Iru-O support notification
ゲジ姉　確か前にも…
Sister Centipede
宇宙ヶ丘公園？
あんな所で肝試しなんかやっても怖くないじゃない
Sister Centipede... I'm sure I've heard this before...
それが　出るって噂だよ
The Space Hill Park?
What's the point of doing the test of courage there?
空手部の子が言ってた
ホントに？
People say there are ghosts there!
I heard it from a karate club girl.
But really?
八汐君
いや…
Uh, Yashio?
本字幕由諸神字幕組出品,僅供學習交流之用 更多中日雙語字幕，請登錄 www.kamigami.org
---諸神字幕組---
台本：卷
翻译:臭屁匠 苜汐瞳
校对: mam
后期:Ressul zzz
Ah...
すれ違う　言葉の裏に
閉ざされた　心の鍵
Behind the words passing by
The key of my closed heart is hidden
君という　フラグ開錠が
笑顔救えるのなら
If setting your flag
Could save your smile
夏の風誘う　迫真のスコール
The late summer breeze
波長シンクロ
Turns into a midday squall
ロマンチックみたいに　気の利いた言葉も
As we sync our wavelengths
I'm such a bad romantic
見つからないけど　青空を目指すから
Can't even find
Any words with an edge
Still I aim for the blue sky
僕たちは　一つになれる
戸惑いの涙も　夢も
We can become one
As our dreams and confused tears
真実に　引き寄せられるなら
Draw us ever closer to the truth
それは愛しすぎる
魔法の日を
That becomes our beloved
Magical keyword
Incoming mail
Unread
An urban legend
Daitoku Junna
I know about the Space Hill Park too!
But I'm a bit surprised you're interested in urban legends,
Yashio
宇宙ヶ丘公園のことは知ってるよ
I know about the Space Hill Park too!
でも八汐君　都市伝説に興味あったんだね
But I'm a bit surprised you're interested in urban legends, Yashio.
意外だな
まさか　大徳さんがこんなことに詳しいとはな
And I'm surprised you're interested in them too.
Can I call you "brother"?
She doesn't usually act this hyped...
何か普段とテンションが全然違うんだけど
Kai, stop there!
カイ　待った
Come to the club today!
今日は部活出てよ
I told you a local newspaper's coming to interview us about finishing second place in the Robo-One!
地元の新聞社がROBO-ONE準優勝のインタビューに来るっ言ったでしょ
I don't care. Tell them whatever.
俺はいいや
適当に答えといて
Come on!
でも
何言うか考えといた方がいいよ
Think carefully about what you're gonna say.
Some company might decide to sponsor us after reading about us in the paper.
新聞見た会社からスポンサーの話が出てくるかもしれないから
そっか
That's right!
Hey, Kai!
カイ
I'm meeting with Daitoku.
約束があるんだよ　大徳さんと
大徳さん？
With Daitoku?
Oh right, you followed each other today on Twipo...
そういえば　今日いきなり「ツイぽ」でフォローし合ってたよね
Could this be...
まさか
an indiscretion of youth?
若さ故の過ち？
I'll drop by the hangar if I have time.
時間あったら　ハンガー寄るよ
Sure, see yo—
うん　いってら…
Wait, no!
じゃなくて
Around here?
ここら辺？
Yeah.
うん
Did your ears start ringing when you saw it?
八汐君がその現象に遭ったとき　耳鳴りみたいな音聞こえなかった？
Something like "bii-bu-bu-bihyaa"?
ピーブッブー　ピヒャラーって感じじゃない？
Yeah, I guess that's it.
たぶん　そんな感じ
やっぱり
Then it's true.
Is there some rumor?
何か噂があるの
What's this?
それは？
The Buzzer.
The Buzzer
It's a short-wavelength radio broadcast in Russia.
ロシアの短波ラジオなんだけど
For about thirty years now, it's been airing just this buzzer sound non-stop.
30年くらい前から　ずっとこのブザー音だけ流し続けているの
この音は電離層の研究に伴う音じゃないかって説も有力で
The popular theory is that it's related to research of the ionosphere.
You know, the JAXA's nearby here...
ほら　ここすぐ近くにJAXAがあるから
So there's a possibility they're broadcasting something similar?
似たような音を出している可能性もあるってことか
Then my PokéCom froze because of that too?
じゃあ　ポケコンがフリーズしたのもその影響とか？
That seems to have happened to everyone in Japan.
そっちは日本中であったみたいだけど
The problem's the email and the girl you saw.
問題はメールと女の子の方だよ
That's closer to the occult than urban legends.
そっちは都市伝説というよりオカルトかな
Are those different in any way at all?
その2つはどう違うの
They're completely different!
全然　違うよ
The occult's all about ghosts and stuff!
オカルトは幽霊とか関係してるから
It's scary!
怖い
There have been rumors about it for a while.
前からちょくちょく噂はあるんだ
Minamitane Folk Museum
There's a ghost in Space Hill Park.
宇宙ヶ丘公園に幽霊が出るって
Minamitane Folk Museum
A long-haired junior high schooler girl—
中学生くらいで　髪が長い女の子で…
Look, there!
あっ　あそこに
出るわけないでしょ　こんな昼間に
Come on, no ghost would show up in broad daylight...
You're mean.
意地悪
But you sure made me shiver.
でも　ちょっと背筋が冷たくなったのは事実
The girl I saw was just as you described.
俺が見たのはまさにそんな感じの女の子だったから
Huh?! Really?!
ホント
Actually, she's been reported in other spots too,
実はここ以外にも目撃された場所があるみたい
for example Chikura cave.
千座の岩屋とか
Chikura cave
Hmm, there?
あそこか
Wanna go?
行ってみる？
I live that way too.
私のうち　そっちだし
Sure, but can I drop by the hangar before that?
いいけど　その前にハンガー寄ってってもいいかな
The hangar?
ハンガー？
You mean... the Robotics Club's?
もしかして　ロボット部？
Yeah. Problem?
嫌？
ごめんね　ロボットは…
Sorry, I don't like robots...
Ah. Well, it's not like I've got anything in particular to do there.
別に特別用があるわけじゃないから
Let's go to the beach then.
行こう　海岸に
Okay. Sorry...
ごめんね
Then again,
では　あらためまして
let me introduce you to
これが　そのガンつく1です
the GunPro-1!
Uh, but... Could we please focus on the Robo-One?
あの　ですから　それよりもROBO-ONEの話を…
I get it!
分かってます
But we in the Robotics Club focus not on tournaments past,
ただ　うちとしてはすでに終わった大会のことではなく
but rather our future endeavors!
これからの未来に向けての活動について…
What are you blabbering about by yourse—
何1人でごちゃごちゃしゃべって…
Is he a club member?
部員の方ですか
Yeah, second year Hidaka.
はい　2年の日高君です
Wait, what're you holding in your hand?
その手に持ってるのは…
Ah, this...
こ…これは
Isn't that the champion M45?!
優勝したM45ですよね
No, that's not...
いや　これはそういうんじゃにゃくて
間違いないですよ
No, I'm certain!
何でここにあるんですか
Why is it here?
Huh? It's because that hobby robot's Hida—
何でって　そりゃ
そのホビーロボットは日高君の…
Ouch!
いったぁ
What're you doing?!
何すんのよ
Pardon me.
失礼
It's here because Mister Pleiades came here to train before the world championship.
実はミスター?プレアデスが世界大会を前に
練習試合をしにここまで遠征に来ているのです
Oh, I see.
そうなんですか　何だ
Come on, say that first!
それならそうと早く言ってくださいよ
That's the kind of thing we want to hear about!
そういう話を聞きたいんです
Okay...
The reporters are here.
So nervous!
No sign of her at all.
何の反応もないねぇ
Yeah, it doesn't look like it's about to freeze, and there's nothing...
特にフリーズする様子もないし　何の問題も…
何だ
Huh?
The cadaver of a whale.
鯨さんの亡きがらだね
There have been quite a lot of them recently.
最近　多いんだよ
Not so long ago 14 of them were thrown ashore at once.
この前は14頭も一度に打ち上げられていたって
Ah, back in March?
3月くらいだっけ
Worms and frogs are dying a lot too.
あと　ミミズさんの大量死とか
カエルさんも
There are so many weird things about this island.
何か　この島色々変なんだよ
It's not just the island.
それは島だけじゃないんじゃない？
ほら　今年の冬ロシアは夏みたいに暑かったっていってたし
Don't you remember how last winter was as hot as summer in Russia?
And even now the American west coast is covered in snow.
アメリカの西海岸は今雪だっていうし
I heard some of the Nazca Lines were washed away by the rain too.
ナスカの地上絵も雨で流れたとか
Oh right. Now that you mention it...
そっか
そういえば　そうだね
And of course no one has any idea what could be causing it.
結局　原因は分からずじまいってことか
But it's weird, isn't it?
何か　でも不思議だよね
Like the SS Anemone incident.
あねもね号のときみたい
Thanks for today.
今日はありがとう
This is for tagging along with me.
付き合ってくれたお礼
You're such a klutz. Want another?
下手だねぇ　交換する？
It's fine.
大丈夫
You've got practice tomorrow?
あしたから　また練習？
You mean karate? Nah, it's over already.
空手？　もう終わったよ
The tournament's over, so we third years are retiring.
大会終わったから　3年生は引退だよ
成績は？
How did you do?
1回戦負け
Lost in the first round.
You're weak?
大徳さん　弱いんだ
Yeah, I am.
弱いよ
I hoped I'd get somewhat better if I trained for three years in high school...
高校でも3年間やれば　少しは成長するかなあって思ったんだけど
じゃあ　ロボ部入れば？
Then why don't you join the Robotics Club?
But I'm a third-year!
私　3年生だよ
So are Aki and I.
俺もアキちゃんも3年生だよ
But I don't like robots...
でも　ロボットは…
I get it. There must be something.
分かってる　何かあるんでしょ
But why not just drop by the club room at least once?
でも　一度くらい部室来てみれば？
アキちゃんが苦手だっていうんなら別だけど
Though it's okay if you can't get along with Aki.
No, I've got no problem with Senomiya.
瀬乃宮さんは全然苦手じゃなくって
On the contrary, I'd be happy to get along with her even better.
むしろ　もう少し仲良くなれたらっていうか
Then what're you waiting for?
それは貴重だよ
Aki will be overjoyed if I tell her.
聞いたら　アキちゃん絶対喜ぶ
Thanks! I'll think about it.
ありがと　考えておく
おまけ
A present.
By the blessing of the Seven Sisters,
7人の女神の祝福により
I descend from four hundred lightyears in space!
われ　400光年のかなたよりここに降臨
I am Mister Pleiades!
アイ　アム
ミスター?プレアデス
もう帰った
They left.
Gunvarrel Ankh Striker!
ガンヴァルアンクストライカー
Hey, Aki.
やっほー　アキちゃん
Knock!
ノック
Yeah, yeah.
まあまあ
How was the interview?
取材はどうだったの
So-so.
まあまあ
And the space candy CEO?
スペースアメの社長は？
Didn't you say you'll meet once more?
もう一回会いに行くって言ってたよね
No luck.
駄目　タネガシマシン3を持っていってみたんだけど
I brought the Tanegashimachine-3 along, but no luck.
It's so tiny...
ちっちゃいのぉ
It lacks impact!
インパクトが足りん
ボイン　ボイン　ボンキュッボン
You should take Subaru along.
昴君連れていけば？
Impact is something he's good at.
インパクトだけは絶大だし
I tried to get him to...
さっき誘ってみたけど
How could I?
行くわけないでしょ
Are you nuts?
部長はバカですか
その格好で言われると　怒りもひとしおね
Being told that by a guy wearing that costume really pisses me off.
What should I do?
もう　どうしよう
Anyway, good luck.
まっ　せいぜい頑張って
And here we go, you say it as if it had nothing to do with you.
はい出ました　人ごと発言
ガンつく1のパイロットはカイなんだからね
You're the pilot of the GunPro-1!
またその話？　俺は嫌だってば
This again? I told you I don't wanna.
転倒したらただじゃ済まないでしょ
I'd be in hell of a mess if it fell over.
It won't fall!
転倒しません
Even though you listen to Subaru...
もう　昴の言うことは聞くくせに
ひど過ぎるよね
You're so mean.
なら　アキちゃんも勝負する？
Then wanna fight?
So Daitoku fought you too and won?
じゃあ　大徳さんもカイと勝負して勝ったんだ
Huh? That's different.
あれは違うよ
I asked her to tag along with me.
俺から頼んだの　連れてってほしいって
Where to?
どこに？
We visited some famous urban legend spots.
都市伝説スポット巡り
Really?
何それ
Oh, why so curious?
あれ？　気になっちゃってる？
嫌だ　何言ってるの
Come on, what're you saying?
別にカイが大徳さんとデートしてても　うちは気にしないよ
You can date Daitoku all you want. I don't mind.
でもほら　あんまり誰かと遊びに行くとかなかったから
It's just that I thought it's unusual, since you've never really hung out with anyone before.
珍しいな　なんて
じゃなくて
Um, I was meaning to ask if you're
curious about urban legend spots...
都市伝説スポットって何なのか気になるって聞いたつもりなんだけど
カイめ　やるようになった
Damn you, Kai! You've gotten better!
At what?
何が
Just shut up!
うるさい
What's wrong with you?!
何だよ　痛ててて
Ouch!
Stupid!
こんにゃろ
You have 1 new message.
Oh, it's just Mom?
何だ　母さんか
New message
Remaining
Re: Don't forget dinner!
Mom
I'll be home soon.
Warm the miso soup please!
Well, ghosts never show up when you want them to...
まっ　こういうのは待ち構えてると現れないっていうしね
...ar me?
聞こえますか
Sister Centipede
Here it comes!
来た
Sister Centipede
Is somebody there?
誰かいますか
The popular theory is that it's related to research of the ionosphere.
この音は電離層の研究に伴う音じゃないかって説も有力で
Radar tower
Nothing changes even if I get closer.
近づいても特に変化なしか
I'm not supposed to freak out just yet.
俺が驚いてどうする
End of the line, huh?
これ以上は駄目か
I think this had an infrared camera too...
確か赤外線カメラのアプリが…
What's this?
何だ　これ
What password?
パスワード？
I know!
愛理　知ってますよ
Can I tell you?
教えてあげたいです
You're... in this room?
いるのか　この部屋に
Yes, I'm here.
います
愛理の声　届いてないのかと思ってました
I was afraid you couldn't hear me.
しゃべってる
She talks...
Can I call you "brother"?
お兄ちゃんって呼んでいいですか
I'd like to talk with you!
お話ししたいです
お話し？
Talk?
Testing-testing!
テステス　テステス
Tomorrow the weather will be clear
あしたの鹿児島県　種子島屋久島地方のお天気は晴れでしょう
in the Tanegashima-Yakushima area in Kagoshima prefecture.
Can you hear me?
ちゃんと聞こえてますか
An AI?
AIか
Yeah, I can hear you. It's a lot clearer now.
聞こえる　クリアになったよ
I'm really good at talking.
愛理はですね　お話が得意です
I can say your name too, Brother.
お兄ちゃんの名前だってちゃんと言えます
八汐海翔さんです
It's Yashio Kaito.
何で知ってる
Why do know my name?
説明が欲しいですか
Do you want me to explain?
だったら　愛理をタップしてゲジ姉を呼んでください
Then tap me and call Sister Centipede.
Come on.
ささ　どうぞ
アクセス確認　ゲジ姉モードに移行しました
Access mode confirmed. Switched to Sister Centipede mode.
You're Sister Centipede?
君が　ゲジ姉
Airi is a communication interface running on the Iru-O servers.
愛理は『居ル夫。』サーバー内に常駐して
コミュニケーションを行うインターフェース
Sister Centipede is classified as a fully automated information gathering engine.
ゲジ姉は　全自動情報収集エンジンと位置づけられております
So? How do you know about me?
それで
俺のことを何で知ってるわけ
Airi has been in use since December 24th, 2008.
愛理の運用が開始されたのは　2008年12月24日
You were visiting the park even then, and as your age was close to Airi's age setting,
そのころから　公園に来る八汐さまを見て
愛理の設定年齢とも近かったため　最優先接触対象に選択されました
you were chosen as the prime contact candidate, Master Yashio.
Contact was attempted 29 times in the past 8 years.
接触を図ろうとしたのは8年間で29回
You showed reactions on 3 occurrences.
そのうち　八汐さまが反応を示したのは3回
This is the first instance of successful contact.
こうして接触に成功したのは今回が初めてとなります
そんなに…
That many times?
So you're an Iru-O app that happened to take a liking to me?
要するに君は「居ル夫。」のアプリで
たまたま俺を気に入ったってこと？
That is an adequate description, Master Yashio.
そういうことになります八汐さま
Could you stop calling me that?
その八汐さまって　やめない？
So you wish to register a nickname?
ニックネームを登録したい　ということでしょうか
Please continue.
では　どうぞ
Uh, I don't know... Something like Mr. Yashio or just Yashio...
まあ　妥当なところで　八汐さんとか　八汐君とか
Are you sure you wish to register "Something like Mr. Yashio or just Yashio"?
まあ妥当なところで八汐さんとか八汐君とか
で　よろしいですか
Cancel that. Just "Yashio."
キャンセルで　八汐さん
Canceled. Registered as "Yashio."
キャンセル　八汐さんで登録しました
Yashio!
八汐さん
Yep.
はい
So, how do I get rid of you?
で　君を消すにはどうすればいい？
Should I press here?
ここを押せばいいの
Warning. Guests are denied access to this operation.
警告　ゲストユーザーにはアクセス権はありません
ジオタグにパスワードを入力してください
Enter your password in the GeoTag.
This is that thing from before.
これは　さっきの
Your password is h-i-d-d-e-n-h-a-n-d, "hiddenhand."
パスワードは　hiddenhandヒドゥンハンドです
This feels so much like a trap...
わなにしか思えないんですけど
Hiddenhand.
ヒドゥンハンド
Document Viewer
These are secret files on the Iru-O servers.
このデータは　『居ル夫。』サーバー内のシークレットファイルです
Kim
Kimiji
Kimijima
Kimijima Re
Kimijima Repo
Kimijima Report
Document Viewer
Codename: Kimijima Report No. 1.
コードネーム　君島レポートナンバー1
It was written on November 7th, 2009 by Kimijima Kou.
2009年11月7日に君島コウによって記述されました
Kimijima Kou?
君島コウ
This report is a backup in the event of my murder.
これは　仮に私が殺された時のバックアップとなるレポートである
Someone is threatening me.
私は何者かに脅迫を受けている
恐らく遠からぬ未来に抹殺されるであろう
I feel that I will be killed in the near future.
NASAは重大な事実を隠蔽している
NASA is hiding an important fact.
In November 2000, an investigation of the Sun's south pole area
2000年11月に太陽の南極圏を調査した際　磁気単極子
confirmed the existence of magnetic monopoles.
つまり　モノポールは間違いなくここに存在していたのだ
However, NASA launched a thorough propaganda campaign
しかし　NASAは徹底したプロパガンダを行い
and made the leaked truth appear as a falsehood.
一部流出した事実を完璧に嘘だと人々に認知させた
だが　科学的根拠により
But scientific research concludes that the Sun will soon explode.
太陽が爆発寸前まで来ているのは紛れもない事実なのだ
In 2012, 15, 19, and 20, there will be a series of gargantuan solar flares.
2012　15　19　20と　連続で大規模な太陽嵐が発生し
特に15年の太陽嵐は　地球と地球磁気圏に深刻な影響を及ぼす
The solar flare in 2015 will have the most grave effects on Earth and its magnetosphere.
世界中の誰も知らないまま　重大な危機をもたらす力が
The people will be ignorant of the great threat closing in on them from the Sun.
太陽から到来することになるのだ
Stories about solar flares and NASA conspiracies are quite popular.
太陽嵐の話とか　NASAの隠蔽とかは確かによく聞くけど
So that means that he might've been a crackpot,
じゃあ　単に妄想に取りつかれて書いたとか
or he wrote it as a part of a sci-fi novel, right?
SF小説の一部とかいう可能性もあるわけだよね
Yeah, I think so.
だと思う
でも　ナンバー1ということはナンバー2があるってことだよね
But if it's the "No. 1" then there must be a "No. 2" too, right?
We can't tell until we've seen that too. And...
それ見てみないと　それに…
And?
それに？
His solar flare predictions were accurate.
太陽嵐のことは正確に予見しているよ
That aurora in the sky has been in Japan since '12.
12年から日本でもオーロラが見られるようになったんだし
2012, 15, 19, and 20, huh?
2012　15　19　20年か
What are you doing here so late?
何だ　こんな時間に
相変わらず　お奇麗で
You're pretty as always.
If you wanna use the bench, buy something.
ベンチ使うんなら　何か買ってけ
The '15 Crash...
15年クラッシュ
They did say computers around the world went haywire due to a solar flare...
そうか　世界中のパソコンがおかしくなったのも
太陽嵐のせいだって言ってたっけ
What's with that complicated look on your face? It's not like you.
何　難しい顔してんだ
お前らしくもない
I know, right?
ですよね
いや　変なもの見つけちゃって
I found something weird. It's by this guy called Kimijima Kou...
君島コウって人のなんだけど
Where did you hear that name?
どこで　その名前を
やはり一瞬だが　常軌を逸した動きを見せている
There's definitely erratic behavior, however momentary it might be.
Something was off back then. I felt it in my gut.
あのとき感じた違和感は気のせいではなかったようだ
I have finished my report. Do you wish to read it?
報告をまとめました
ご覧になりますか
Tell me.
聞こう
Yashio Kaito. Born May 5th, 2001. 18 years old at present.
八汐海翔　現在18歳　2001年5月5日生まれ
鹿児島県　種子島出身
He is from Tanegashima, Kagoshima prefecture.
A victim of the SS Anemone incident.
あねもね号事件の被害者の1人です
幼い思い出　眩しい波光に
The blinding light of childhood memories
夢に見た景色は
Turns the scenery of my dream
Into monochrome as it lies forgotten
置き忘れたまま
モノクロになって
瞳から消える
And vanishes from my eyes
だけどいつでも君は
But you've always been
Looking straight at the future
まっすぐ明日を見つめた
どれくらいの涙と引き換えに
And you paid the price in tears
だから僕らの迷いも
So we turn our hesitation
強さに変えてくれる
Into strength by the power
Of our connected hearts
繋がった心が解き放つ
Feel it! These overflowing emotions
不意に溢れ出す思い
For that someone in the sunset
同じに誰かのために
I'll use what little courage I have
この小さな勇気で
風が吹き荒れても
And overcome the rage of the wind
Because I want to protect you
君を守りたくて
Airi!!
Tune in next week too!